How's it going everyone?
This is a free video from the coding interview course that I released earlier this year interview espresso.
This one's about binary trees.
I hope you enjoy it.
And if you want to check out my course, there's a ton more videos like this one.
Welcome to the next overview video.
In this one, we're saying goodbye to the linked list and hello to the binary tree.
We can think of a linked list as the shallow end of data structures when there's a whole
Ocean out there.
In fact, both the linked list and the binary tree are part of a family of node -based
Data structures.
By now, we're quite familiar with creating list nodes with a value property and setting their next pointer.
You might be surprised to hear this, but a ton of data structures have these very same components.
That is a node containing a value property and one or more pointers.
So think of nodes as the bricks that we're using to build different quite literally structures.
So within the broad category of node -based data structures,
We have everything from graphs,
With multiple pointers going from top to bottom.
Most trees look more like a pyramid than a tree,
But if you squint, you can see the tree if you flip it upside down.
Let's get more precise.
Trees expand in one direction,
So that means no cycles.
And the HTML on any page can be represented as a tree.
And in fact, you can store anything in a tree with a hierarchical nature that is parents and
The most interview algorithms associated with it.
Now each type of tree has a specific set of rules.
And the main rule for a binary tree
With the properties left and right.
That is to say, left and right pointers.
Comparing this to the linked list where we have a single dimension,
.nags.nags.nags, here we have 2 dimensions left and right.
Went through to get here,
Well, this is called a branch.
So you might hear variations of following an entire branch, following a path to the end,
Things like that when we talk about traversing through trees.
More often than following one complete branch though, we'll want to look at every node in our tree,
Whether we're searching for something modifying the values,
Pulling them out or just doing any number of different things.
So the important question becomes,
What order do we look at our nodes in?
The best answer is it depends.
And this question is actually at the core of a lot of binary tree problems.
So as you can imagine, if we're processing every node in the tree in some way, whether that's
As simple as just printing out each node's value or something a bit more complex,
As simple as just printing out each node's value or something a bit more complex, (có vẻ đoạn này hơi dài lặp — giữ nguyên nội dung)
We're going to talk about in a few problems.
This type of tree is a binary search tree.
Note the binary search in binary search tree.
The reason why it's called that is because like the binary search algorithm that uses a list or
Now as far as what exactly balance means, well, we've got a whole video dedicated to that coming
Up soon.
Than its right child's value.
So in this tree, three is more than one and less than five.
So we can call this a valid binary search tree.
Not only that simple rule, but this greater on the right,
Less on the left principle has to be true for the entire tree.
Let me explain. If I put a node with value two as five's left child,
Our sub tree with five and two passes.
But unfortunately, we are breaking it within the greater context of the tree because it's down our right
And we have another whole video dedicated to that coming up soon.
Now if we know we do have a valid BST,
The way we find something is by simply traversing towards the value we want.
But five has no right child.
So we can safely say that eight is not in our tree.